nottingham.ac.uk 2014-06-25

# Privacy and Cookies - The University of Nottingham

References in this privacy policy to "The University", "we", "our", and "us", etc. are references to us, The University of Nottingham. 

The University is committed to protecting your privacy and respecting the confidentiality of information which you provide when you visit our website at <http://www.nottingham.ac.uk/>. At the same time, we want to try to ensure that you obtain full value from our website and from the services which you may want to receive via our website. 

The University is registered as a data controller under the Data Protection Act 1998 (the "1998 Act"). [The Data Protection Register](http://www.ico.gov.uk/ "The Data Protection Register") is open to view. We uphold the relevant data protection principles and process all personally identifiable information about you ("personal data") in accordance with the 1998 Act and other relevant legislation. This privacy policy explains what information we may collect about you when you visit our website and how we may use it. 

You should read this privacy policy in conjunction with the University's website terms of use, of which this privacy policy forms a part. By agreeing to our terms of use, you are consenting to our processing of your personal data in accordance with this privacy policy. Any changes to this privacy policy will be posted on our web site and, where appropriate, notified to you by email. 

##  The information we collect 

It is possible to use our website without providing any personal data. However, the University may automatically collect certain information about you when you use our website, including by our use of "cookies" (see below), such as the IP address of your computer and the dates and times of your visits. 

In some areas of our website the University may ask you for personal data, such as your name, address and email details, that will enable us to make your site visit a more rewarding experience for you and/or to contact you after your visit. Examples of this might be where you complete an online form asking for a copy of a prospectus or to book a place on an open day with us, where you ask for information about a job vacancy, or where you subscribe to an online newsletter. 

In some other areas of our website, where you can register as an online user, the University may ask you for more detailed information about yourself. An example of this is Nottingham Alumni Online, which, amongst its various other services, enables former students to make contact with each other. In order to provide these types of services, it may be necessary for us to collect and process additional personal data, such as information about your educational history. 

##  How we may use this information 

Personal data which we collect about you via our website is held on and processed by computers situated at The University of Nottingham. The University will retain this data for a reasonable period or for as long as the law requires. 

The University will not disclose any of your personal data collected via our website to any third party, other than in circumstances set out in this privacy policy and/or where you have given us permission to do so, unless we are required to do so by law. 

The University may use personal data collected from you via our website to manage and monitor use of our website. Otherwise, we will only use this personal data for the purposes for which it was collected, unless you have given us permission to use it for other stated purposes. For example, if you supply us with your name and address so we can send you a prospectus for a particular department, and at the same time you agree that we may send you similar information in the future, we may subsequently invite you to an open day at that department. 

There may be circumstances in which the University will ask you to agree to us disclosing your personal data to certain third parties, or transferring it outside the United Kingdom. However, we will not do this without your permission. For example, if you use Nottingham Alumni Online, we may ask you to agree to us transferring your personal data to countries outside the United Kingdom, including those which do not have equivalent data protection legislation to the 1998 Act. This is because some alumni are likely to be located outside the United Kingdom, and the global nature of the Internet is such that making personal data available to others on our website is likely to involve the transfer of this personal data to other countries. However, before transferring your personal data in these circumstances, we will do our best to ensure that appropriate arrangements are in place to protect your privacy.  

If at any time you want to withdraw any permission you have given us to provide you with services, or to use your personal data in any other way, please inform us by [email](mailto:data-protection@nottingham.ac.uk "email").  

##  Cookies 

When you visit our website the University may send "cookies" to the browser on your computer, even if you do not provide us with any personal data. Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your device when you visit a website. Cookies are sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognises that cookie. Cookies are useful as they enable us to recognise you (by a unique number allocated to you) when you return to our website and so to personalise your return by, for example, customising web pages based on which areas of the website were previously of interest to you. If you have previously provided us with personal data, then cookies may enable us automatically to fill in your name and other information when, for example, you complete an online form. 

Cookies also enable us to compile anonymous, aggregated statistics which help us to understand how our website is used and how we may improve it. It is not possible for cookies to read personal information on your computer and/or to find out any personal information about you.  

A list of the different cookies that are used on this website are set out below. We have categorised these to help you understand the type of function the cookies are performing. 

###  Strictly Necessary Cookies:

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the website. Without these cookies, some of the services you have asked for could not be provided. 

Cookie Name  |  Purpose  |  Further Information   
---|---|---  
ASP.NET_SessionId  |  Stores technical information only. This is essential to the operation of the site .  |  This cookie is deleted automatcially at the end of your browsing session   

###  Performance Cookies: 

These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies do not collect information that identifies a visitor and all information collected is aggregated and therefore anonymous. These cookies improve how a website works. 

Cookie Name  |  Purpose  |  Further Information   
---|---|---  
__utma  |  Used by Google Analytics to track user count of visits to a site, when a first visit was, and a last visit.  |  This cookie is deleted after two years   
__utmb  |  Used by Google Analytics to track exactly when a user visits a site.  |  This cookie is deleted after 30 minutes   
__utmc  |  Used by Google Analytics to track exactly when a user leaves a site.  |  This cookie is deleted when you close your browser   
__utmz  |  Used by Google Analytics to track how a user got to this site (where from), what link was used, what part of the world  |  This cookie is deleted after six months   
We use analytic information to help us make our website more focussed and better for our website visitors.  You may, however, [opt out of Google Analytics tracking](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en "Analytics Opt-out at Google") if you prefer.   

###  Targeting Cookies: 

These cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. They also limit the number of times you see an advertisement and help to measure the effectiveness of a campaign. They are usually placed by advertising networks with the website operator's permission. They remember that you have visited a website and share this information with other organisations such as advertisers. 

Cookie Name  |  Purpose  |  Further Information   
---|---|---  
We do not use Targeting Cookies on the website.  If you use Google services, and are logged into your Google account while browsing our site, it is possible that Google may track your activity alongside our use of the Google Analytics service for targeting purposes: please check [Google's privacy statements](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ "Google privacy statements")  

##  Subject Access Requests 

Under the 1998 Act you are entitled to be told if the University holds any personal data about you. If we do hold any personal data about you, you are entitled to be given a description of the data, to be told for what purposes the data are processed, and the people (or classes of people) to whom the data may have been disclosed. A request for a copy of information held about you is called a "Subject Access Request". To make a subject access request, please contact our Data Protection Officer. Please note that we are entitled to, and do, charge a fee of £10 for providing this information. 

##  Security 

Our website and our computer systems have security measures in place with the aim of protecting the loss, misuse or alteration of personal data held by us. 

##  Other websites 

Our website may contain links to other websites which are outside the University's control and are not covered by this privacy policy. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of any such linked websites. 

##  Comments or questions 

Please send any comments or questions relating to this privacy policy to our [Data Protection Officer](mailto:data-protection@nottingham.ac.uk "Data Protection Officer").
